Guide to the Department of Chemical Engineering records, 1949-2007 UA 346
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Department of Chemical Engineering records
1949-2007
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 346
1 Linear Feet (2 box)
This collection contains correspondence and lecture notes from faculty of the Department of Chemical Engineering.
Historical Note
In 1921, after the hiring of A. J. Hartsook, Chemical Engineering became a separete program. The department has grown and changed its name to the Department of Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering in 2005. For more information please see: https://chbe.rice.edu/Content.aspx?id=102
Scope and Contents Note
This collection contains correspondence and lectures from members of the Department of Chemical Engineering faculty.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Accruals Note
Additional materials are expected for this collection.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; Chemical engineering -- Study and teaching; Education
- Series I: General, 1949-1990, 173260
  - Correspondence - Armeniades, Constantine, 1987-1990; 173261 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Carnahan, Norman, 1987-1989; 173262 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Dyson, Derek, 1984-1987; 173263 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Glacken, Michael, 1987-1988; 173264 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Leland, Thomas, 1984-1986; 173265 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Miller, Clarence A., 1984-1989; 173266 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Robert, Mark, 1985-1990; 173267 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Assorted, 1986-1990; 173268 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Absorption Apparatus" Project - Walker J. Duffie and John P. Buettner, 1949; 173269 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Lecture Notes on Vector Analysis with an Introduction to Tensor Analysis" - John E. Plapp, 1958; 173270 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Workbook and Notes taken at Bettis Reactor Engineering School (1 of 2), November 1957-May 1958; 173271 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Workbook and Notes taken at Bettis Reactor Engineering School (2 of 2), November 1957-May 1958; 173272 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Series II: Drawings and Photographs, 1975-2007
  - Drawings by D. Heath, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, 1975-2007 (Box 2, Folder 2)